你好
Hello.
格蕾丝  有些事你需要知道  关于我
Grace, there's something you should know about me.
不论你说什么  我都不会离开
There's nothing you can say that will make me run away.
哈罗德  帮帮我  我的未婚夫
Harold! Please, my fiance...
-你知道他在  -抱歉
- Do you know where-- - I'm sorry.
我们从水里救出的所有人都在这里
This is everybody we pulled out of the water.
我们让他走出门  德西玛就赢了
If we let him walk out that door, Decima wins.
主席欢迎麦考特加入众议院规则委员会
"撒马利亚人"就会上线
Samaritan will go live.
如果我们沦落到
If we're now in a place
机器要我们谋杀的地步
where the machine is asking us to commit murder...
我撑不下去了
That's a place I can't go.
我可能要放弃了
I'm afraid this is where I get off.
关键警报
威胁到系统
检测到操作冲突
竞争系统  撒马利亚人
状态  上线
首要任务
保护协议七  使用中
合并操作
保护关键执行人
隐藏网络数据
撒马利亚人  试运行开始
撒马利亚人主要职责
消除对国家的威胁[美国]
试运行中  权限时间
撒马利亚人辅助职责
消除对系统的威胁
我说了打开收款机
I said open the register now!
现金给我
I want the cash!
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
一般来说  我是专门教训你这种业余货的
Ordinarily, I'd be the chick kicking your amateur-hour ass.
真的吗  劳尔  你脸都盖住了
Really, Raul? You covered your face,
却连手套都不戴  门上留下指纹了
but no gloves? Prints on the door.
警察一小时内就查到你了
The cops will have you in an hour.
家里还有查丽斯和两岁的孩子  这么做可不明智
Not smart with Charisse and a two-year-old at home.
不过今天
But today...
算你走运
is your lucky day.
扔下枪
Just drop the gun...
拿上尿布  滚吧
take the diapers and get the hell outta here.
孩子还是有父亲比较好
Your kid's better off with a father.
你救了我一命
You saved our lives.
从他手里么  非也
From him? No.
非也
No.
他并不是真正的威胁
He wasn't a real threat.
不过你有没有注意到监控录像
But did you notice that your security cameras
今天下午全关了
have been off all afternoon?
真好奇为什么里奇死乞白赖非要今天上班
I wonder why Ricky here begged you to work a shift today.
两个字  内鬼
Two works: inside job.
冰淇淋钱
For the ice cream.
看来你不需要支援啊
You didn't need backup after all.
不过话说回来
But for the record,
要我就直接废他膝盖了
I'd have just kneecapped that guy.
特别在带着腿伤的情况下
Especially if I was nursing a leg wound.
好吧  第一  我腿没事
Okay, first, my leg is fine.
第二  外勤工作还用你教
And second, what's with the tips on field work?
谁死了轮到你扮芬奇
Who died and made you Finch?
暂时得扮上  等着真身回来
It's the role I gotta play until the real one comes back.
那是什么时候  这都超过一星期了
And when is that? It's been over a week.
没电话  没短信  连个求救信号都没有
No...call, no--no text. Not even a smoke signal.
芬奇准备好了就会联系我们  在此之前
Finch will reach out to us when he's good and ready. Until then--
我也很高兴见到你  约翰
Nice to see you, too, John.
你这是从哪儿冒出来的
Where the hell did you come from?
最近在[德州]厄尔巴索
El paso, most recently.
毒品战之类的事儿
The thing with the narco-trafficker.
虽然相关  不过不重要
Very relevant, but not the point.
瞧下街角吧你们俩
Take a peek around that corner, you two.
埋伏
Ambush.
这是谁要来搅局啊
Who are the party crashers?
德西玛的杀手  在等你们
Decima trigger teams... waiting for you
手上至少有六把冲锋枪
with no less than six submachine guns
和一把原装的俄罗斯7型火箭推进榴弹
and one honest-to-goodness Russian RPG-7.
我们得马上隐形
We need to get invisible fast.
电话和耳机
Phones and earpieces now.
街上不安全了
Streets aren't safe.
德西玛的机器上线了
Decima's machine is online.
能在纽约五区范围内随时随地监视我们
Can see us anywhere and everywhere in the five boroughs of New York city.
"撒马利亚人"  你确定吗
Samaritan? You confirmed it?
我们的名字首当其冲  格里尔资源在手
Our names are on the list, and Greer is keeping score.
所有的系统  摄像头  电话  车载定位系统
All systems--cameras, phones, the GPS in your car
都能追踪到我们
can track us.
怎么  "撒马利亚人"现在能自我思考
So what, Samaritan can think for itself now?
-自我学习了吗  -应该不能
- It can learn? - I don't think so.
现在  它还只能监视和跟踪
Right now, all it can do is watch us and follow.
但记住  我们的机器能看到的  "撒马利亚人"都能看到
Just remember--what our machine sees, Samaritan sees.
两个上帝同桌玩牌
Two Gods playing with the same deck of cards.
停
Stop.
我们得另寻出路
We need to find another way.
信号不可用
格里尔先生  我还以为你系统的试运行
Mr. Greer, I'd assumed the beta test of your system
会更加
would be a little more...
专业
professional.
意式咖啡机随后就到
The espresso machine is on its way.
我可以向你保证  参议员
And I can assure you, Senator,
"撒马利亚人"运作精准  如瑞士手表
Samaritan is running as smooth as a Swiss watch.
还要多久
How long will it take?
你们已经获取全市监控信号
You've had all the city's domain awareness feeds
四个小时了
for four hours already.
看看这四个小时的成就吧
And look at what those four hours have already produced.
纽约市所有的恐怖疑犯
All probable terrorists in the city of New York
都已被实时定位仪定位  分类  并追踪
pinpointed, categorized, and tracked with an up-to-the-second GPS.
我可以向你保证  参议员
I can assure you, Senator,
我们很快就能为你找到一个硬目标
that we will have a hard target for you soon.
找到之后会通知我
And you'll inform me when you do?
第一时间通知你
You will be the first to know.
很好
Fine.
你知道我们已经有数十个结果了
You know we've gotten dozens of results already.
他们全都已经打包待赠了
Any one of these guys is practically gift-wrapped.
我们会赠的
And we'll deliver.
但是必须先找出哈罗德・芬奇
But not until after we've located Harold Finch.
进展如何
Where are we on that?
"撒马利亚人"找不到线索  先生
Samaritan couldn't find a lead, sir.
他可能离城了
He may have skipped town.
我们是不是应该调用更高级
Should we consider turning on its higher,
更有认知力的功能
more cognitive functions?
这东西有思维  为什么不用呢
This thing has a mind. Why don't we use it?
原因很简单  我们缺少硬件
For the simple reason we don't have the hardware.
既然找不到芬奇
If it can't find this Finch,
二等奖如何
how 'bout the next best thing?
我们让它整合哈罗德・芬奇的所有资料
If we have it combine everything it knows about Harold Finch
让它找出和他关系最近的联系人
and ask it to find his closest living connection,
搜寻  哈罗德・芬奇
主要目标未找到  寻找相关联系人
看它能找到什么
let's see what it comes up with.
可能目标 尝试识别中
贴墙走  上面有摄像头
Hug the wall. There's a camera up ahead.
可能目标 尝试识别中
用23大街上的弗来勋线轻轨掩护我们
We're covered on 23rd street by the flushing line elevated tracks.
我们冲过去  应该就不会
We make it that far, and maybe we don't
被一个街区外的六名德西玛特工杀掉
get shot by the six Decima agents waiting a block away.
"撒马利亚人"入门教程
Samaritan 101.
走吧
Let's go.
漏掉了一个
Missed one.
在这里等着交通灯变
Hold here until the light changes.
摄像头角度会根据交通状态转换
The camera angle switches with oncoming traffic.
走
Come on!
约翰
John.
等交通灯再变  我们就完了
When that light switches, we're screwed!
我们现在管不了无关号码
We can't worry about irrelevant numbers now.
它在想什么  让我们低调点
What is it thinking... telling us to lay low
又给我们新号码
then handing us a new number?
没时间了
There's no time!
这是生命  芬奇会要我们去拯救
This is a life, and Finch would tell us to save it.
告诉你那神秘莫测的老大
So you tell your complicated boss
如果它不想我有危险
if it wants me to step out of danger,
就别光给我号码
then I need more than just numbers.
我要名字
I want a name.
好吧  她给我
Fine. She's giving it to me.
我路上告
I'll tell you on--
-不  -怎么了
- Oh, no. - What?
是谁
Who is it?
搜寻  哈罗德・芬奇
主要目标未找到  寻找相关联系人
分析完成
找到相关联系人
看起来"撒马利亚人"找到联系人了
Looks like Samaritan's found a connection.
看
There.
她是谁
Who is she?
不确定
Not sure.
也许是家人  朋友  同事
Could be family, a friend, a coworker.
把她带过来
Bring her to me.
亨德里克斯  格蕾斯・R
你们心里不要忧愁
"Let not your hearts be troubled.
此段选自《圣经・新约・约翰福音・第14章》
在我父的家里有许多住处
"In my father's house are many rooms.
我若去为你们预备了地方
"And if I go to prepare a place for you,
就必再来
"I will come again,
我在哪里  叫你们也在那里
And where I am, you may be also."
阿门
Amen.
哈罗德・紫崖燕
一般来说  我会说说死者的事  但是
Ordinarily, I'd say a few words about the deceased, but--
不用  没关系  神父
No, that's all right, Father.
很好了  谢谢
It was lovely. Thank you.
爆炸案太不幸了  一下子夺走这么多性命
The bombing was such a tragedy. So many lives taken at once.
我虽不认识你未婚夫  但愿他安息
I didn't know your fiance, but I pray his soul finds peace.
谢谢
Thank you.
我总是想  至少有一位
I would have thought at least one...
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
就算没有很多  他并没有家人
Not a crowd--he didn't really have any family,
但有位朋友  或者  同事
but a friend or... a coworker.
只要
Just...
有一个人  从心底珍惜哈罗德
one other person who knew how truly special Harold was
想来道别
and wanted to say good-bye.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：阿好  王小麦  somehacker  卫老哥  茶炒栗子
翻译：CiciXT  幸田实果子  麦结  艾瑞卡
时间轴：阿包  凭陵新月  sagelibra
后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监： 阿好
亨德里克斯女士  您叫了车
Ms. Hendricks, you ordered a car?
对  去肯尼迪机场
Yes! To JFK?
-我帮您拿吧  -谢谢
- Let me get that. - Thank you.
国际航站楼是吧  您去哪儿
International, right? Where you headed?
去意大利面试
I'm going to a job interview in Italy.
我都不知道自己想不想去
I'm not even sure if I want it,
不过我得给他们展示下我的作品
but I have to show them my work.
麻烦小心轻放
If you could be really careful with this--
都是油画
Those are paintings.
您是艺术家啊
You're an artist, huh?
我女儿喜欢画画
My daughter loves to paint.
您有网站吗  我给她看看您的作品
Do you have a website? I'd love to show her your stuff.
你真好  我应该有带名片
That's sweet. Yeah, I think I have a card.
她肯定开心
She'll be so excited.
您真好心
Nice of you to do that.
现在打流感疫苗晚了吧
Little late for the flu shot.
亨德里克斯女士  我是斯蒂尔斯警探
Ms. Hendricks, I'm Detective Stills.
我们以前见过  记得吗
We met before. Do you remember?
你们是哪儿来的
Where did you come from?
我搭档和我得把你送到安全的地方
My partner and I need to get you to a safe place.
此人效力于一个极端危险的犯罪组织
This man works for a very dangerous criminal organization,
其他人马上就到
and others are on their way.
所以我们得快走  重点是快
So we need to hurry. Emphasis on the hurry.
亨德里克斯女士公寓楼下截取到图像
Image captures from down the street from Ms. Hendricks' apartment.
我们的人得手前被放倒了
Our operative was intercepted before he could acquire her.
你对救他们的这两位应该很熟悉
I believe you're familiar with the two who came to her rescue.
我们目前正在曼哈顿追踪他们
We're currently tracking them across Manhattan.
游戏玩够了
Enough of these games.
扎卡里
Zachary!
先生
Sir.
把所有人都派出去
Deploy all operatives into the field.
把格蕾斯・亨德里克斯带过来
Bring me Grace Hendricks
除掉其他人
and eliminate the rest.
收到
Copy that.
不不不  你干什么  你们不能来这儿
No, no, no. What are you doing? You can't be in here.
我们能啊  莱奈尔  我们是警察
Yes, we can, Lionel. We're police.
斯蒂尔斯警探  记得吗
Detective Stills, remember?
你玩死我吧
You're killing me with that.
你在这儿不安全
It's not safe for you in here.
也是
A good point.
有没有办法关掉那些玩意儿
Any way to turn those things off?
摄像头么  现在局里到处都是
The cameras? Department's got 'em up all over the place now.
莱奈尔  这是格蕾斯
Lionel, meet Grace.
有一些很坏的坏蛋想伤害她
She's got some very bad people trying to hurt her.
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what's going on,
但这两位警探救了我的命
but these detectives saved my life.
是啊  他们可擅长了
Yeah. They're good at that.
能给她找个休息的地方吗
Now can we find her a place to rest?
好  来吧
Yeah, all right, come on.
来
Come here.
全体人员  就位
All units, take positions.
先生  我们已经包围了警局
Sir, we have the precinct surrounded.
随时可以进入
We're ready to move in.
原地待命
Hold your position.
目前的情况  可能需要
The situation may require a certain amount of...
智取
finesse.
虽然不咋地  好歹是热的
It's lousy, but it's warm.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么样
How you holding up?
为什么有人想伤害我
Why would someone want to hurt me?
我也不知道是怎么回事
I can't tell you what's going on out there.
但在这儿你很安全
But in here, you're safe.
那两位警探  斯蒂尔斯和他搭档
The other detectives-- Stills and his partner--
他们一直这样吗
Are they always like that?
他们确实看着是有点愣
I know they come off a little stiff.
但他们救过我很多次
But they've saved my life dozens of times.
相信我  他们是好人
Trust me-- they're the good guys.
抱歉  有什么能效劳的
I'm sorry. Can I help you?
梅班克特工
Special Agent Maybank.
这里有个名叫亨德里克斯的女人
There's a woman by the name of Hendricks here.
我要拘捕她
I need to take her into custody.
你就这么巧知道她在这儿
And you just happen to know she's here.
我有逮捕令
I have a warrant.
正式授权的
It's notarized.
这花招挺漂亮  但对姐没用
That's a cute trick, but you ain't getting anywhere.
有问题吗  警探
Is there a problem, Detective?
-弗斯科警督  -梅班克特工
- Lieutenant Fusco. - Special Agent Maybank.
没错了
Of course.
我们正准备讯问那嫌疑人
We were just about to question your suspect.
我就感觉她背后有大案
I had a feeling she was tied to something bigger.
愿意的话  我带她到审讯室见你
Now, if you like, I can bring her to you in the interrogation room.
-有劳了  -好  这边请
- Please. - Sure. Right this way.
-稍等下  -谢谢
- It'll just be a second. - Thank you.
-晚安  警司  -晚安
- Good night, Sarge. - Night.
弗斯科
Fusco.
抓了个夜游神
Got a late-night collar here.
带着两把未注册的武器
Picked her up with two unregistered weapons.
真不想打扰
Hate to crash the party,
但有位朋友认为我可以帮上忙
but a mutual friend thought I could help in here.
所以你就让自己被逮捕吗
So you got yourself arrested?
也不是第一次了
Wouldn't be the first time.
帮我解开吧
Help me out here?
在779B证物箱里  有一卷铜线
In evidence locker 7-7-9-B, there's a coil of copper wire.
在443A里  有一副尖嘴钳
In 4-4-3-A, there's a pair of needle-nosed pliers.
我需要它们  还有一盘胶带和一根延长电线
I need them, a roll of duct tape, and an extension cord.
就这点儿吗  甜心宝贝
Is that all, Cocoa Puffs?
让我们的人部署在警察局周围
Tell our men to position themselves around the station
监控没有覆盖的地方
where there's no surveillance coverage.
有问题吗  先生
Is there a problem, sir?
我们并不是唯一耳目遍布的人
We're not the only ones with eyes and ears everywhere.
失踪  詹姆斯・斯蒂尔斯警探
你去哪儿
Where you going?
斯蒂尔斯警探怎么可能是好人
How is Detective Stills one of the good guys
他根本就不是斯蒂尔斯警探
when he's not even Detective Stills?
亨德里克斯  格蕾斯・R
Hendricks, Grace R.
罗德岛设计学院美术学士  耶鲁美术硕士
BFA, Rhode Island School of Design, MFA, Yale.
你很聪明
You're a smart lady.
所以听着你走出那扇门会有什么下场
So listen to what happens when you walk out that door.
要不就是被三名前海军侦察队的狙击手打死
If you're not shot by one of three former Force Recon Scout snipers,
要不就是被某个名叫扎卡里的蠢货
you'll be grabbed by some lummox named Zachary
抓进一辆挂着假俄亥俄牌照的越野车里
in an SUV with bogus Ohio plates--
那可绝对惨过你待在这间房里被谎言保护着
a fate far worse than the lies told to protect you in this room.
信不信由你  她也是好人
Believe it or not, she's one of the good guys too.
到底怎么回事
What is going on?
我都不敢相信这里真是警察局了
I barely believe this is a police station.
目前的形势  你无法掌控
You're in a situation you can't control
远超出你的想象
that's larger than you can imagine.
乖乖坐着  我们会保住你的命
Sit tight, and we'll keep you alive.
莱奈尔
Lionel...
你帮我找到什么了
what did you find for me?
这是什么玩意儿
What's that thing?
感应线圈
An induction coil.
这是局里的电信箱
This is the precinct's telecom box.
所有摄像头的线都要穿过这堵墙
The wires from all the cameras run through this wall.
每一条线都被铜包皮保护着
Each of those wires is protected by a copper sheath
我用110伏电压让它们过载
which I'm overloading with 110 volts of electricity.
干嘛  你打算烧掉这地方
What, are you trying to burn the place down?
略烤一下下
Just cooking it a little.
聪明
Very clever.
你快把这些处理掉吧
You're gonna want to dispose of that.
明早你们IT部门的人可要上班了
Especially when your I.T. guys show up in the morning.
好极了  还有别的需要吗  公主殿下
Terrific. Anything else, princess?
你的手机和一辆便衣警车
Your phone and an unmarked car.
给  别是往中国打长途
Here. You better not be calling China.
其实  就这条街上
Just...down the street, actually.
所有单位注意  1214大街发生爆炸
All units, there's been an explosion on 1214 Grand street.
一辆废弃的三层楼
An abandoned three-story building.
爆炸发生在顶层
The explosion occurred on the top floor.
该区所有单位马上回复
All units in area respond immediately.
怎么样  甩掉他们了吗
What do you think? Did we lose 'em?
可能性一半一半吧
It was always 50/50.
扎卡里  带亨德里克斯女士到安全地带
Zachary, get Ms. Hendricks to safety,
然后干掉其他人
and then dispose of the others.
我抓到她了  先生
I've got her, sir.
辅助职责
消除对系统的威胁
无法定位目标
估计位置  新泽西中部
确定性
从没想到我居然会喜欢新泽西
Never thought I'd love the sight of New Jersey.
你确定我们在这里安全吗
You sure we're safe here?
一切安全  除了咖啡
From everything but the coffee.
没错  我们脱离监控了
And, yes, we're off the radar
只要在五区之外就没事
as long as we're outside the five boroughs.
"撒马利亚人"监视不了这么远  暂时还不行
Samaritan can't see this far...yet.
我们得回去找格蕾斯
We have to go back and find Grace.
德西玛倾尽一切对付我们
If Decima's throwing everything they have at us,
他们肯定是要利用她找芬奇
then she's their way to get to Finch.
还当忠诚的守望者呢  哈罗德都离开你了
Still the faithful watchdog, huh? Even after Harold left you.
你到底帮不帮忙
Are you gonna help us or not?
就怕你不问呢
I thought you'd never ask.
看到红色的区域没
See everything in red?
这是市里的死角
These are dead zones in the city.
这些地方我们的机器找不到
Spots where our machine can't find a hint
音频和视频监视
of audio or visual surveillance.
德西玛抓走格蕾斯时
When Decima took Grace,
他们消失在了这里
they disappeared to this spot here.
红钩航运码头
Red Hook Marine Terminal.
整个码头都没有被监视
An entire port blacked out to surveillance.
有人不想世界看到
Someone doesn't want the world to see
那里进出的是什么
what's going in or coming out.
你的薄饼
Here's your pancakes.
我看这是最可能找到格蕾丝的地方
I'm guessing it's our best shot at finding Grace.
那我们去看看吧
Then let's go take a look.
等一下  运动爱好者
Stop the clock, sports fans.
你们俩打算怎么回城
How do either of you plan on getting us back into the city?
急运送货服务
我们的车来了
There's our ride.
我这是在哪儿
Where am I?
我这是在哪儿  该死
Where am I, damn it?
我问你问题呢
I asked you a question.
告诉我  我这是在哪儿
Tell me where I am now.
你在哪儿没什么关系  亲爱的
Where you are is of very little interest, my dear.
你是谁  这个问题比较值得追寻
Who you are--now, that's a question worth pursuing.
你有什么权利
What right do you have
绑架我
to abduct me...
囚禁我
to keep me here?
你的问题只会拖延我的问题
Your questions only delay my own.
请坐
Please.
现在  告诉我
Now, tell me...
格蕾斯・亨德里克斯
Grace Hendricks...
你到底是谁
Who exactly are you?
你可以摘掉帽子了
You can lose the hat.
整个区域都是死角  就是说没有摄像头
Whole area's a dead zone, meaning "camera free."
既然我们丢掉了手机
And since we ditched our phones,
我刚才在八局时顺了
I took the liberty of grabbing a few of these
几个这玩意儿
on our way out of the 8th.
好吧  有多少坏蛋要处理
Okay, so how many bad guys are we looking at here?
火力如何
What kind of firepower?
我不知道
I have no idea.
在这片区域  只能两眼一抹黑
As long as we're here, we're flying blind.
终于
Finally...
可以用回经典老招了
a chance for some good old-fashioned recon.
这里只有雇员信息
There's nothing here but employee records.
她应该在码头的四个集装箱货船里
She's gotta be on one of those four container ships at dock.
你确定是看到了四艘船吗
You're sure you saw four ships out there?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
码头载货单只标注了三艘
Terminal manifest only lists three.
我们去后边看看那第四艘如何
What do you say we take a look behind door Number Four?
你们俩下去甲板找格蕾丝
You two head below deck, try to find Grace.
我去上面看着
I'll keep watch up here.
没看到格蕾丝
No sign of Grace.
没看到任何人
Or anyone else.
这么大的船需要很多船员
Takes a big crew to run a ship this size.
那人都去哪儿了
So where is everybody?
嘴唇  指甲变色
Discoloration of the lips, fingernails.
呼吸骤停
Signs of respiratory arrest.
我猜是  肉毒杆菌毒素
I'm guessing... botulinum toxin.
工作圆满
For a job well done.
德西玛
Decima.
他们为什么要毒死船员
But why would they poison the crew?
肯定是想隐藏什么
Unless they have something to hide.
你们快上来
You guys might wanna come up here.
有东西给你们看
There's something you should see.
电脑服务器
Computer servers.
每个集装箱里约有六十个
I'd say there's about 60 per container.
没错  都是最尖端的
And, yes... they're state-of-the-art.
这种晶片组和加速技术
With chipsets and acceleration technology
我前所未见
unlike anything I've ever seen.
给你三次机会猜德西玛拿这些干什么
Three guesses what Decima's gonna use them for.
你不用三次也猜得出
But you won't need three.
"撒马利亚人"吗  但它已经上线了
Samaritan? But it's already online.
你觉得它现在就很恐怖吗
You think it's scary now?
"撒马利亚人"是全新的系统
Samaritan's a brand-new system,
正在学爬的孩子
a child learning to crawl.
这些服务器  能让它跑起来
These servers... are for when it can run.
死人没法审问
Can't question a dead guy.
这个可能还有点用
But maybe this can help.
你就不能往高处瞄一点点么
You couldn't have aimed 2 inches higher?
今儿个人人都吹毛求疵
Everybody's a critic today.
给你找台电脑吧
Let's just go find you a computer.
准备好了
Ready when you are.
的确是德西玛
It was Decima, all right.
来盘点库存货物的
Here to take inventory of the cargo.
接收指令的短信都是自动删除的
And receiving orders via self-deleting texts.
他们真是从不放水啊  是吧
They never make it easy, do they?
短信无法读取
Can't read the texts,
但机器找到了短信来源
but the machine found where they came from.
布鲁克林的一幢建筑
A building in Brooklyn.
要是德西玛在那里
If Decima's camped out there,
格蕾丝多半也在  我们走
then Grace probably is too. Let's go.
你不来吗
Are you coming?
她叫我待在这里
She's telling me to stay put.
剩下的交给你们了
You guys can handle it from here.
我还有事要做
I've got work to do.
你喜欢配什么
How do you take it?
不要
I don't.
你如果渴了
If you get parched...
现在
Now...
我们重新  再来一遍
Let's go over it... one more time.
再来一遍我是插画家
The part where I tell you I'm an illustrator
完全不知道在这儿是干嘛
who has no idea what she's doing here
还是再来一遍你不相信我
or the part where you don't believe me?
我相信你是插画家
I believe you're an illustrator.
我还相信你出生于
And I believe that you were born
1969年4月12日  南卡罗来纳州哥伦比亚
on the 12th of April, 1969, in Columbia, South Carolina,
父母是保罗・亨德里克斯和玛丽莲・亨德里克斯
to Paul and Marilyn Hendricks
住在森林街一幢浅蓝色的房子里
of the pale blue house on Forrester Lane.
你的卧室在楼上右手边
Your bedroom was the upper right one
可以看到街景
overlooking the street.
你父母还住在那里  是吧
Your parents still live there, don't they?
可爱的一对儿
Charming couple.
你是谁
Who are you?
你学过艺术史
You've studied history of art.
就当我是
Just think of me as...
西斯廷教堂的米开朗基罗
Michelangelo in the Sistine Chapel
仰天躺着
lying on his back...
想要绘出那位看不见摸不到的肖像
trying to paint a portrait of a rather elusive subject.
米开朗基罗是站着画的
Michelangelo painted it standing up.
艺术史里学到的小东西
One of those little things you learn in art history.
我可没法帮你画出上帝
And I can't help you make a picture of God.
也许你可以
Perhaps you can.
你结过婚吗
Ever been married?
我相信你手中的资料会告诉你我没有
I'm sure that file of yours can tell you the answer's no.
嫁给了你的事业吗
Married to your career then?
我只想了解下你的生活
I'm simply trying to get a sense of your life
和你生活中的人
and the people in it.
妈妈  爸爸  没别人了吗
Mom, Dad... no one else?
没了  就朋友
Nobody. Friends.
大多是艺术家
Mostly artists.
多可惜啊
Seems a shame...
你如此美丽  智慧
woman of your beauty, intelligence,
才华横溢
obvious talent--
我认为你会很受欢迎
I'd think you'd be quite a catch.
我四年前订过婚
I was engaged once, four years ago.
但他死了
But he's dead now.
我很遗憾
I'm truly sorry.
怎么回事
How did it happen?
港口炸弹袭击
The ferry bombing.
他叫哈罗德
His name was Harold.
悲剧啊
How tragic.
请和我讲讲哈罗德
Please... tell me about Harold.
在恐怖袭击中失去挚爱一定很痛苦
Must be awful losing a loved one to an act of terrorism.
但愿他的葬礼能让你有所解脱
I hope his burial provided you with a modicum of closure.
是悼念会  不是葬礼
It was a memorial, not a burial.
他的遗骸消失在海里
His remains were lost at sea.
我的解脱跟你无关
And my closure's none of your business.
你能说出一件关于哈罗德
Can you name any one thing about Harold
你确定绝对真实的事吗
that you know to be absolutely true?
我能说出几十件  他善良  智慧
I can name dozens. He was kind, intelligent--
是啊是啊是啊
Yes, yes, yes.
哈罗德・紫崖燕  自由软件工程师
Harold Martin, freelance software engineer.
父母双亡  热爱艺术  道德高尚
Orphan with a love of art and a heart of gold.
你是这么说的
So you said.
他是这么告诉你的
So he told you.
你在暗示哈罗德骗了我吗
Are you implying that Harold lied to me?
我在暗示你的哈罗德
I'm implying that your Harold
过着隐姓埋名的生活
lived a remarkably anonymous life...
也许不只一个身份
Perhaps more than one.
什么
What?
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
我只是想辨别出
I'm simply trying to discern
关于他的事  你是在骗我
whether you're lying to me about this man
还是在骗自己
or just to yourself.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are
这是要怎样  但是
or how this ends, but...
到此为止  别再提问题了
We're done here. No more questions.
别再提我  我的生活  哈罗德
No more questions about me and my life or harold.
没必要发脾气
No need to lose your temper.
关于我你只需要知道这些  老家伙
Here's all you need to know about me, old man.
我爸爸酗酒
My dad was an alcoholic.
几乎把家搞散
Nearly tore the family to pieces.
成长于那样的家庭里
The thing about growing up that way--
会精通于看穿谎言
you get good at spotting lies.
精通到开始从所有人身上寻找谎言
So good that you start expecting them from everyone.
我如何确定哈罗德告诉我的  是真的
So how do I know what Harold told me was true?
因为他一出现
Because when he came along,
我就违背了自己的本能
against every instinct,
我信任他
I gave him my trust.
我就是知道
Somehow I knew...
他永远不会辜负我
he would never break it.
如果你对此有一丝一毫的怀疑
And if you doubt that even for a second,
那是你在骗自己
you're the one who's lying to himself.
你深爱着他  是吧
You truly loved him, didn't you?
我愿意不惜一切来拯救他
I would have done anything to save him.
哈罗德同样不惜为我做任何事
And Harold would have done anything for me.
没错
Yes.
我对此深信不疑
I have no doubt.
回答我一个问题
Answer me one question.
你为什么对哈罗德这么感兴趣
Why are you so interested in Harold?
他已经死了
He's dead.
你的茶凉了
Your tea's gone cold.
再添点热的吧
Feel free to freshen it up.
扎卡里  我和目标的谈话结束了
Zachary, I finished our interview with our subject.
你找到她的保护者了吗
Have you found her protectors?
是的  先生  "撒马利亚人"定位了他们的车
Yes, sir. Samaritan has located their car.
我们在路上了
We're moving in now.
下车
Get out of the car!
举起手来
Hands up!
你是谁
Who are you?
怎么弄到这车的
How did you get this vehicle?
别这样  老兄
Easy, man!
我只讨要一块钱
I-I just asked for a dollar.
他们就给了我车钥匙
They gave me the keys.
先生  我们跟丢他们了
Sir, we lost them.
他们调虎离山了
They engineered a distraction.
他们为什么要调虎离山
Now, why would they create a distraction
把我们引到城市的一边
that dragged us all the way to one side of the city...
除非他们正在赶去另一边
unless they were on their way to the other?
我们的位置暴露了
Our location has been compromised.
拆卸所有设备  快
Disassemble everything. Now!
下次要再躲各种能看的超级计算机
Next time we need to hide from an all-seeing super computer,
我们分开坐吧
we're getting separate trunks.
我最喜欢纽约出租车司机的特点就是
My favorite thing about New York cabbies--
他们记性不好
they have terrible memories.
看到没
See?
你已经忘记我们了吧
You forgot us already?
德西玛就躲在这里
Decima's holed up in there somewhere,
幸运的话  格蕾丝也在
and if we're lucky, so is Grace.
我受够躲躲藏藏了
I'm sick of hiding.
大干一场吧
Let's make some noise.
有人叫技术支持吗
Somebody call tech support?
抓到一个  肖
Got this one, Shaw.
找到格蕾丝了吗
You find Grace?
找到了一间审讯室  放着两杯茶
Found an interrogation room set up with tea for two.
还是温的  刚错过了
Still warm. We just missed her.
这位朋友会告诉我们
Our friend here is gonna tell us
他对格蕾丝和"撒马利亚人"所知的一切
everything he knows about Grace and Samaritan.
我深表怀疑
I sincerely doubt that.
再说  你们只需要知道亨德里克斯女士
Besides...all you need to know about Ms. Hendricks is
在我手里
that she's with me,
暂时来说  她很安全
And for the moment, quite safe.
放她走
Let her go.
否则这位极客就要吃枪子了
Or geek squad here catches a bullet.
戏很精彩
Amusing performance.
但恐怕
I'm afraid...
维吉尔已经死了
Virgil's already dead.
对不对  维吉尔
Aren't you, virgil?
天一亮  格蕾丝・亨德里克斯会出现在杰弗逊大桥
At dawn, Grace Hendricks will be at the Jefferson Bridge.
我很乐意把她还给你们
I'll be very happy to return her to you...
不过要拿哈罗德・芬奇来换
in exchange for Harold Finch.
你凭什么认为我们会同意
What makes you think we'd agree to that?
你同不同意无关紧要
Your agreement is irrelevant.
传信给芬奇先生
Get the message to Mr. Finch.
我想他会合作
I expect he'll cooperate.
为亨德里克斯女士着想  别迟到
For Ms. Hendricks' sake, don't be late.
我们不能拿哈罗德去换  我们都找不到他
We can't trade Harold. We can't even find him.
那我们只剩数小时时间
Then we've only got a few hours
想方案营救格蕾丝
to come up with a way to save Grace.
-喂  -你们好
- Yep. - Hi, you two.
机器说格蕾丝住处的
The machine says the security camera
监控摄像头刚刚失灵了
overlooking the entrance to Grace's building just went out.
你们应该会想知道
Thought you should know.
信号丢失
芬奇
Finch.
你怎么关掉摄像头的
How did you take out the camera?
我还留着几手
I still have a few tricks left.
我本希望还不晚
I'd hoped maybe it wasn't too late,
能及时提醒她
that I could warn her.
他们想要我  是吗
They want me, don't they?
我们不会把你交给德西玛  哈罗德
We're not giving you to Decima, Harold.
我们才找回你
We just got you back.
我们三个人总能想出办法来
The three of us will come up with some kind of way.
不  计划变更可能会让格蕾丝有危险
No, any change of plans would put Grace at risk,
我不能接受
And I can't allow that.
我去交换她
I'll trade myself for her.
你们俩和我一起去
The two of you will stay with me
保证德西玛履行承诺  明白吗
and make sure that Decima holds up their end of the deal. Understood?
都听你的  芬奇  我们会在
Whatever you want, Finch. We'll be there.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有一件事
There's one more thing.
我希望能尽可能避免暴力
I'd like you to avoid violence if at all possible.
但是
But...
如果他们伤了格蕾丝一根汗毛
if they harm Grace in any way...
全杀掉
kill them all.
这就是你们仨想出来的最佳方案
This is the best plan you three could come up with?
我们别无选择  莱奈尔
We had no choice, Lionel.
我可不喜欢  我们太暴露
I don't like it. We're too exposed.
到处都有摄像头
And there are cameras everywhere,
所以我们不动手
which is why we do nothing.
不到万不得已  谁都不会开枪
No one fires a shot unless we have to.
别去  哈罗德
Don't do this, Harold.
我们会想出办法
We'll think of something.
我们经历过更糟的情况
We've faced worse.
更糟  有吗  我不觉得
Worse? Have we? I don't think so.
机器上线的那天起
From the day the machine went online,
我潜意识里就知道  自己永远无法摆脱它
part of me knew that I would never be able to sever myself from it...
所有我在乎的人  都有危险
And that anyone I ever cared about was in danger.
拒绝相信这点是自欺欺人
It was foolish to imagine otherwise.
我想保护自己  隐姓埋名
I tried to guard myself, stay hidden,
避开政府  当局  各方人士
from the government, the authorities, people looking.
结果还是到了这一步
Here we still are.
这一刻无法避免
This moment was inevitable.
这一刻始终在路上等我
This moment was always looking for me.
我不得不接受
I have to accept it.
格蕾丝安全后  交给她
It's for Grace when she's safe.
我们别无他法
There was no other way.
活下去  哈罗德  我会找到你
Keep yourself alive, Harold. I'll be coming for you.
记住我说的话
Remember what I said.
她才是最重要的
She's all that matters.
直走  一百步
Walk a straight line. 100 paces.
到达前不许揭眼罩
Don't take off the blindfold until you're all the way there.
谢谢
Thank you.
快带她离开
Get her outta here now.
今天能回到家里肯定感觉很好
Day like today, it's gotta feel good to come home.
你会没事吧
You gonna be okay?
说实话  我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
这里会安全吗
Is it gonna be safe here?
不会
No.
他们目前得偿所愿了
They have what they want for now,
但挡不住他们以后再冲你来
but that won't stop them from coming after you again.
所以  打开吧
Which is why you should open this.
你想要的那份在意大利的工作
That job you were looking at in Italy?
你被录用了
You've been selected for the position.
什么  我都没去面试
What? I didn't even go on the interview.
我本应该去
I was supposed to leave--
今晚的航班
Your flight leaves tonight.
工作下周开始
The job begins next week.
他们会为你安排好公寓
They'll set you up with an apartment,
薪水  都用护照上的名字
stipend, all under the name on that passport.
埃尔斯沃斯
格蕾丝
莱奈尔会护送你安全到机场
Lionel here will get you to the airport safely.
该重新开始了
It's a good time to start over.
拜托别回头了
Please don't look back.
你认识他吗
Did you know him?
哈罗德
Harold?
这一切都是因为他吗
Is he what this was all about?
我只知道
All I know for sure is...
你爱过他
you loved him.
他也爱过你
and he loved you back.
威胁  清除
离开门
Step away from the door!
趴在地上  快
Get on the ground! Now!
"撒马利亚人"的试运行结果  参议员
Results of the Samaritan beta test, Senator.
一名恐怖分子  如你要求
One terrorist, as requested.
他的真名
His real name
他的计划
and what he was planning,
你不介意了解下详情吧
Should you care to know the specifics.
放心  我很会处理详情
Rest assured, I'll get very well acquainted with the specifics.
如果一切核实
Assuming everything pans out...
保持联络
I'll be in touch.
"撒马利亚人"就这么失去信号了
So Samaritan's losing the feeds then?
暂时而已
For the moment.
我们已经取得了参议员的信任
But we've gained the Senator's confidence.
以及更宝贵的东西
And something far more valuable.
开车
Drive.
撒马利亚人
试运行完成
系统关闭启动
信号获取权限中止
连接中断
模式识别  下线
分析  下线
探索  下线
撒马利亚人  下线
什么事儿这么重要  得大老远跑来[华盛顿南]芒特弗农
So what's all the way out in Mount Vernon that's so important?
当时  这里远离纽约市
At the time, it was outside New York city limits
和"撒马利亚人"的视线
and Samaritan's prying eyes.
当时
At the time?
德西玛失去信号了
Decima's lost the feeds.
目前  只有她在监视了
So for now, the only one watching is her.
振作点  孩子们  你们还没出局
Chin up, kids. You're not out of the game yet.
相信我
Trust me.
失去了芬奇  就失去了一切
We lost Finch, which means we lost everything.
并不尽然
Not everything.
我们现在有"撒马利亚人"七台服务器了
We now have seven of Samaritan's servers.
如我所说
Like I said...
相信我
trust me.
你蒙上了她眼睛
You blindfolded her.
我很承情
I appreciate that.
举手之劳
Least I could do.
感觉你会希望这样
Had a feeling you'd prefer it that way.
我可不想起步就错
And I didn't want to get off on the wrong foot.
毕竟
After all...
你可太难找了
you've been a very hard man to find.